瓦格斯塔夫秋季音乐剧就在今夜
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
-你儿子全搞砸了  -我儿是闪耀之星
- Your son ruined everything! - My son is a star!
翻译  小布拿拿   斯人   Tiogy   Iz
淡定  琳达  淡定
Calm down, Linda, calm down.
尼尔・帕特里克・哈里斯:  美国著名演员
他长大就是尼尔・帕特里克・哈里斯
He's the future Neil Patrick Harris!
时间轴  深夏桃子
得了吧  尼尔・帕特里克・哈里斯
What? Neil Patrick Harris
比吉恩厉害多了
is way more talented than Gene.
后期  斯人   总监  Iz
安静  各位
Quiet down, everyone!
多谢
Thank you.
现在  还有一堆家长小孩在外面
Now, there's a lot of parents and children waiting out there
等着看秋季音乐剧
that came to see the fall musical,
但我们这好像起了点冲突
but it seems that we have some conflict going on here.
还好  所有冲突都有个敌人  就是我
Luckily, conflict has one enemy: Me.
现在我要拿出我的和气宝典
So I'm going to get out my peace pad
来处理这个烂摊子  平息这场纠纷
and we are going to process this mess and put it to rest.
现在  谁告诉我发生了什么
Now, who wants to tell me what happened?
我来说
I'll tell it!
凭什么他来说
Well, hey, why does he get to tell it?
因为他是我的宝贝小帅哥
Because he's my beautiful boy, that's why.
是啊  你只是个爹
Yeah, and you're just someone's dad.
是啊  是我爹
Yeah, my dad.
同志们  别这样  吉恩
People, please! Gene.
事情要从校园广播说起
It started with the school announcements.
注意了  瓦格斯塔夫的同学们
Attention Wagstaff student body.
秋季音乐剧要开演了
The fall musical is coming up,
1978年上映的一部美国歌舞片
今年我们不会再演《油脂》了
and we're not doing Grease again.
我受够了  我肯定不做了
I can't! I'm not doing it!
今年  我们将采用
For this year, we will be accepting
学生上交的原创作品
student submissions for an original production.
所以  你们当中如果有
So, if there's anyone out there
-充满创造力  -我
- who's creative - Me.
-有天赋  -我啊
- Talented - Me!
并且有音乐细胞的人
And musically brilliant
就是我
Me!
你们的机会来了
this is your big chance.
对了  今天的午餐是玉米卷
Also, today's lunch is tacos.
玉米卷
Tacos?!
人生巅峰啊
This is the best day of my life!
撕衣庆祝
Shirt rip!
各位  机会来了
You guys! This is it!
我终于可以向世界呈现我的激情之作了
I can finally unleash my passion project on the world!
你是说
Are you talking about...
《虎胆龙威》音乐剧啊
Die Hard, the Musical!
你貌似筹划好久了
You've been working on that one for a while.
是的  自从看了《虎胆龙威》我就觉得
Yeah, ever since I saw Die Hard and said,
怎么没人唱歌呢
why is no one singing?
怎么没人跳舞呢
Why is no one dancing?
好莱坞这帮人都怎么了
What's wrong with Hollywood?
那个嘴里老叼着项链
Who's got a necklace in her mouth,
让人喘不过气  还暗恋你的人来了
is smothering, and like-likes you?
-咱妈吗 - 不  考特尼
- Mom? - No, Courtney.
哦不
Oh, no.
你好  吉恩
Hey, Gene.
好吧  她是想复合
Okay, she wants you back.
我来解决
I'll handle this.
听着  考特尼  我知道你想复合
Look, Courtney, I know you want to get with this.
但是  亲爱的
Okay? But honey...
他简直一团糟
It's a mess.
你看看眼前这坨是啥玩意儿
I mean, what are we even looking at here?
不是  我不是想复合
Uh, no, I don't want to get back together.
我想说音乐剧的事
This is about the musical.
你肯定要表演《虎胆龙威》  对不
I bet you're doing the Die Hard one, right?
我们约会的时候他给我看剧本了
He let me read it when we were dating.
就这样  考特尼  有回忆就够了
That's it, Courtney. Just remember the good times.
简单说  我也想参演
Anyway, I'd love to be in it.
我还参加了嘻哈舞蹈班
And I've been taking a hip-hop dance class...
*我是考特尼*
*I my am Courtney I am*
*我喜欢...  我去...*
*I like to give... and I go to the...*
*我  吼吼  这个*
*I... ho ho, and this...*
*吼吼  结束*
*the ho ho, and now I'm done.*
怎么样
So, yeah.
首先  我很喜欢这段舞
First of all, I love it.
其次  不行
Second of all, no.
因为我不想搞砸我的演出
Only because I want my play to be good.
我完全理解
I totally get it.
那舞很糟糕  我人也很讨厌
That dance was horrible, and I'm really annoying.
好吧  拜拜
Anyway, bye!
什么  我没那样说啊
What? I didn't say that.
我捕捉到了你的话中意
But I think I captured the spirit of your words.
我才不讨人厌
I am not annoying.
-你确实讨人厌  -对  这样说不对
- Well... Yeah, you are. - Yeah, it's bad.
我记着是这样的
Well, I remember it this way.
我可以参加你的《虎胆龙威》音乐剧吗
May I be in your Die Hard musical, please?
不  我要吃玉米卷
No! I like tacos!
-嗯  这听着倒像吉恩  -对
- Yeah, that sounds like Gene. - Yep.
总之  就在那天
Anyway, along came the day
我们都要去表演自己的剧
we were all supposed to submit our plays.
你的秋季音乐剧是什么
So what's your fall musical about?
落叶
Leaves.
*红  黄  桔  棕*
*Red, yellow, orange and brown*
*从树上缓缓飘落*
*They're on the tree then they fall down*
了不起
Good.
等下  里面是谁
Wait, who's in there now?
*我有着女人的激情*
*I've got the passion of a woman*
*我渴望一个开始*
*Looking for her start*
*比我头发更包容的*
*And the only thing bigger than my hair*
*是我的心*
*Is my heart!*
《打工女郎》  福克斯电影公司1987年电影
这只是《打工女郎》里
And that's just one of the amazing songs
众多金曲里的一其中首
from Working Girl, the Musical!
考特尼  你偷了我的点子
Courtney! You stole my thunder!
不  我没有
No, I didn't.
那这就是巧合喽
So it's just a coincidence
你恰巧选了个也是1980年代大热
you took a beloved movie from the 1980s...
且刚好被称为《虎胆龙威》姊妹篇的电影
some say the sassy sister film to Die Hard...
再加上音乐和歌词  这是赤裸裸的抄袭
and set it to music and lyrics? Thunder thief!
不好意思  你那键盘倒是萌得很
I'm sorry, but that keyboard is adorable.
是你从救济站抱回来的吧
Did you rescue it from a shelter?
给力啊  老爸
Nice one, Daddy.
呵呵  那你的键盘是哪来的  道格
Well, where'd you get your keyboard, Doug,
超大型键盘专卖店吗
the Too-Big Keyboard Store?
键盘嘲笑到此为止
Enough keyboard insults.
吉恩  马上就到你了
Gene, it'll be your turn in a minute
到时候我们就能听到你的音乐剧了
and we can hear what you've got.
好吧  那你们可听好了
You'll hear what I've got, all right.
因为好听惨了
Because it is very audible!
*中臣  中臣  中臣  中臣*
*Nakatomi, Nakatomi, Nakatomi, Nakatomi,*
*中臣  中臣  中臣*
*Nakatomi, Nakatomi, Nakatomi.*
好了  就到这吧
Okay, I'm gonna stop you there.
-但我还没  -没关系  别担心
- But I haven't even... - It's fine, don't worry.
谢谢你
Thank you.
彼得  你可以进来了
Peter, you can come in now.
准备好听我的秋季[落叶]音乐剧了吗
Ready to catch my fall musical?
秋天来啦  一起来
It's fall, y'all!
卡莉・西蒙 美国著名创作歌手
勒邦姿老师  我说过我认识卡莉・西蒙吗
Ms. LaBonz, did I mention that I know Carly Simon,
她是《打工女郎》的幕后制作人
the artist behind the Working Girl
以及主题曲"大河奔腾"的演唱者
and "Let the River Run,"
如果演我们的剧  她也会来看的
and if we do our play, she'll come to the show?
就定《打工女郎》了
We're doing Working Girl!
-太好了  -好的
- Yeah! - All right!
我可怜的小宝贝
Oh, my poor baby!
-我的宝贝  -琳  你太用力了
- My baby. - Lin, not so hard.
我们能集中下注意力吗
Can we please stay focused here?
当然了  福旺德老师
We absolutely can, Mr. Frond.
交给我吧
Let me take over.
是这样的  由于我是这么个仁慈的人
You see, being the generous soul that I am,
我得插一手帮帮我哥
I had to step in and help a brother out.
露易丝  我们来开水房干什么
Louise, why are we in the boiler room?
我只想回家钻被窝里去
I want to just go home and crawl into bed
然后大哭一场
and have a good, long dutch oven cry.
打起精神  吉恩
Buck up, Gene.
我每次生日没收到小马时
It's like I scream into my pillow
也会抱着枕头大哭大叫
every time I don't get a horse on my birthday:
明年一定会有的
There's always next year!
各位  这开水房后面
Guys! There's a secret boiler room
有个没人知道的秘密开水房
in the back of the boiler room that no one knows about.
我觉得 那儿以前可能是
I think, in the olden days,
是老师们聚集起来吸鸦片的地方
they used it as the faculty opium den.
好吧  但我们来做什么
Great. So why are we here?
来这是因为这房间
We're here because this room
正好是《打工女郎》
happens to be under the very auditorium
演出礼堂的正下方
where Working Girl, the Musical is gonna be performed.
那就把我埋在这儿吧
Then this is where I want to die!
不  听着  你要让
No, listen! You're gonna put on
地下同人抗议版《龙胆虎威》
the guerilla-slash-protest production of Die Hard,
在这里同时上演
the Musical on the same night, in here!
让那偷你点子的考特尼
It's the perfect way to stick it to Courtney,
领教领教你的厉害
right in her thunder-stealing face!
太棒了
It's brilliant!
有意思
The symbolism!
我们要从舞台下方来个正面袭击
We'll be up-staging her from down-stairs-stage!
不  更棒的是
No, what's brilliant is
我们还要向每人收5美元的门票
we're going to charge five bucks a head.
真是个又周到
What a considerate
-又赚钱的好点子  -我就知道
- and lucrative solution to Gene's problem. - I know!
你是这世上最聪明的人了
You're the smartest person in the whole world!
我就知道
I know!
露易丝最聪明
Louise is the best!
干嘛
What?
瓦格斯塔夫秋季音乐剧就在今夜
怎么要这么久  最烦等来等去的了
What's taking so long? Waiting is gross.
没错  演出得继续啊
Yeah, the show must go on!
这才是正事
That's a thing, right?
吉恩  你违反了
Well, Gene, you violated school rules
禁止进入秘密开水房的校规
by entering the prohibited secret boiler room...
没错
Yup.
你决定在音乐剧之夜私下演出地下同人
You decided to put on a guerilla-slash-protest play
-抗议版《龙胆虎威》  -棒极了
- the same night as the fall musical... - Amazing.
事情对你很不利
Things are not stacking up in your favor here.
你不想听整件事的原委么  福旺德老师
Do you want the whole story or not, Mr. Frond?
天了噜  细枝末节  听整晚都可以
Oh, my God, every word. I could do this all night.
一切都进行得很顺利
So things were really coming together...
音乐剧搞定  演出场所搞定
Okay, we got the musical, we got the venue.
就缺演员了
Now all we need is the actors.
英国著名演员
没错  你认识伊恩・麦凯伦爵士吗
Right. Do you know Sir Ian McKellen?
-不认识  -糟糕
- No. - Crap.
考特尼  纸不错
Hello, Courtney. Cool piece of paper.
吉恩  如果你想参演音乐剧
Gene, if you're here to try out for Working Girl,
《打工女郎》  已经太迟了
the Musical, you're too late.
我正要公布演员表
I'm posting the cast list right now.
不过我也许可以把你加进去
But I suppose I could work you in,
比如演个傻缺订书机
as like a really stupid stapler
或者桌子什么的
or a desk or something.
我演订书机演得可好了
I'd be an incredible stapler!
不过别担心
But don't even worry about it,
-因为我正在筹备  -增肥
- 'cause I'm putting on a pl... - Weight!
由于他没能参演音乐剧
He's putting on a lot of weight,
也不能到处乱讲什么秘密音乐剧
not being in any plays or talking about other plays
他正在筹备增肥
that could get him in trouble.
是的
Oh, right...
祝你增肥成功
Oh, well, good luck with your weight gain.
貌似已经胜利在望了  回见
Looks like you're almost there, bye!
谢啦
Thank you.
各位  我是秘书一号
You guys, I'm secretary number one!
接受事实吧  二号三号
Eat it, two and three!
-我去  -什么嘛
- Aw, man. - Come on!
老妈  看来我没有
Well, Mom, I guess I don't have
电影《打工女郎》中的男主角
青少年版哈里森・福特
the dashing good looks and charm
的帅气和魅力
of a medium-young Harrison Ford.
我想我们找到演员了
I think I've found our cast.
请允许我介绍没能得到考特尼剧里的角色
May I present the people that didn't get cast
但仍然想表演的演员们
in Courtney's play but still want to be in a play players.
对  被刷掉了
Yep, did not make the cut.
我看我只有在摔跤项目上冲刺奥斯卡了
I guess I'll have to win an Oscar for wrestling.
是因为我唱歌和玛丽亚・凯莉一模一样吗
Is it because I can't not sing like Mariah Carey?
*我情难自控*
* I can't help it. *
我们是念台词重叠了
We stepped on each other's lines.
梅金老师  你在这儿干嘛
Miss Merkin, what are you doing here?
我给瓦格斯塔夫音乐剧钢琴伴奏24年了
I've played piano for the Wagstaff Musical for 24 years.
结果道格一来就把我挤走了
Then Doug comes in and pushes me out!
卡西欧会弹么
Well, how are you with a Casio?
应该可以
I think I can manage.
等等  我们还需要一个女生
Oh, wait. We still need a girl
扮演霍莉・甄娜罗・麦克莱恩
to play Holly Gennaro McClane.
《龙胆虎威》中男主人公妻子
-要不你来演  -不可能
- So I guess that's you? - Oh, no way.
除了金发坏蛋我啥都不演
I'm that blond bad-ass guy or nothing.
好吧  那让蒂娜演  她人呢
Fine, then it's Tina. Where is Tina?
《打工女郎》排练进行中
*我是凯瑟琳・帕克*
* I'm Katherine Parker *
凯瑟琳・帕克  主人公苔丝・麦吉尔的老板
*我超级有钱*
* And I'm super rich *
*你很快就会发现我非常*
* And soon you will find that I'm quite a... *
*哔*
* bleep. *
是的  我背叛吉恩去演了考特尼的剧
Okay, so I betrayed Gene by being in Courtney's play,
但是我有一个完美的借口
but I have a perfectly good explanation.
*我是个生意人  我有个计划*
* I'm a business man with a business plan *
*我需要一个会赚钱的老板娘*
* I need a business woman with some business hands... *
就是这样
So, yeah.
天哪
Oh, God.
可你俩的角色最后又不会在一起
But your characters don't even end up together!
不同的人对电影有不同的解读
We're all allowed to interpret the movie differently.
不  他们绝对没有在一起
No, they definitely don't end up together.
一千个哈姆雷特嘛
Eh, to each his own.
他们真的没有在一起
No, they really don't.
[法语]不好不坏
Well, Comme ci, comme ?a.
好吧  你开始自说自话了
All right, well, now you're just saying words.
[法语]这就是人生
C'est la vie.
总之  到了演出前一天
Anyway, it was the day before the big show.
也就是昨天
Some of you might call it yesterday...
明晚我的演出见哦
See you at my play tomorrow night.
我写了一出戏  明天表演  记得来看哦
I wrote a play, we're doing it tomorrow, see you there.
在哪儿  等等  你听见了么
Where? Wait... You hear that?
这声音在说我有演出
It's the sound of me having a play
而你没有  是这么说的
and you not having one! It sounds like,
*我有演出你没有*
* Yeah, I have a play and you don't have a play *
* I have a play, you don't have a play... *
走着瞧  考特尼・惠勒
I'll show you, Courtney Wheeler!
我现在没法跟你说
In a way that I can't tell you about right now!
没关系  再见
So never mind! Bye!
*你为何把尸体扔我车上*
* Why did you throw that corpse on my car? *
*因为我邀请你参加我的派对  伙计*
* 'Cause I'm inviting you to the party, pal *
*我想我们会成为最好的搭档*
* Think we're gonna be great pals *
*艾尔和约翰  约翰和艾尔*
* Al and John, John and Al... *
过来  我要和你摔跤
Now come here. I'm gonna wrestle ya.
-快过来  -好吧
- Get over here! - Okay...
-快来  -不对不对不对
- Come on! - No, no, no, no!
约翰・麦克莱恩在大厦里
John McClane is in a tower.
均为电影《龙胆虎威》中的角色
艾尔・鲍威尔警长在地面
Sergeant Al Powell is on the ground!
你们不能摔跤
You can't wrestle!
-我做了个很有创意的改编  -很大胆
- I made a creative choice. - Very bold.
鲁迪  你手挥舞的太频繁了
And Rudy, you're moving your hands too much.
喘息声也太大
And quit wheezing!
对不起  石棉对我的肺部
I'm sorry, the asbestos might be
可能有一些影响  但我会克服的
affecting my lungs a little, but I'll work on it.
能把暖气关了么
Can we turn down the heat?
就是  热死了
Yeah, it's boiling up in here!
这是开水房  齐克
It's the boiler room, Zeke!
开水房就是这样的
It's what it does!
我感觉你们一点不在乎
It's like you guys don't even
这部旨在打败考特尼并将我们送进百老汇
care about this guerilla-slash-protest musical
的地下同人抗议剧
designed to take down Courtney and send us to Broadway!
吉恩
Gene.
借一步说话
A... A word?
明晚就要演出了
The play is tomorrow night.
我们要振作起来
We gotta get it together.
给他们来个鼓舞士气的喊话
Give 'em a pep talk, you know?
让他们燃烧起来
Put some fire in their butts!
烧他们是鼓舞士气的一部分么
Is the putting a fire in the butt part of the inspiration,
还是新的建议
or is that a separate suggestion?
-我勒个去  -好吧
- Damn it. - Fine.
听着  我写了一出牛逼闪闪的音乐剧
Listen up, I wrote an incredible musical.
我本以为只要我们合力就能打造一部
And I thought together we'd create the kind of theater
惊天地泣鬼神的作品
that would make the gods cry.
但现在我想说  我这是疯了吗
But now I'm like, "What am I, nuts?"
你们把它全毁了
You're all blowing it!
齐克  你的摔跤
Zeke with your wrestling,
达瑞尔  你走调的歌
Darryl and your extra-note singing,
还有鲁迪的疯狂挥臂
Crazy Arm Rudy over here!
安迪和奥利
Andy and Ollie,
联邦探员不会手拉手
FBI agents don't hold hands!
这两个会
These ones do.
没错  他们还睡一张床
Yeah, and they sleep in the same bed.
现在我意识到让这部作品发光
And now I'm realizing that the only way
的唯一办法就是
to make this production shine
把你们都开除  我自己来演
is if I fire all of you and play all the roles myself!
-说啥呢  -除了梅金老师
- Say what? - Except for Miss Merkin.
-你是我的救星  姑娘  -谢谢
- You're my rock, girl. - Thank you.
我还考虑给你弄个鼓
And I've been thinking about getting you drums
或许再选件可爱的上衣
and maybe a cute top.
-你觉得如何  -你说了算
- You cool with that? - You know it.
祝贺各位
So congratulations,
剩下的人都被降级为
the rest of you have been demoted to stagehands
吉恩独角音乐剧《虎胆龙威》的工作人员
on Die Hard, the Musical, a one-Gene show!
万岁
Hurray.
一定很牛逼
It's gonna kick ass.
教导主任  福旺德先生
这么说你开除了所有演员
So you fired the casting,
自导自演《虎胆龙威》么
and made Die Hard, the Musical a one-man show?
没错  吉恩领衔主演
Yes, starring me. Gene. Yeah.
现在该到了
Okay, well, I've come to the part
指责父母的时候了  鲍勃  琳达
where I blame the parents. Bob, Linda...
嗨
Hi.
-我要批评你们  -好吧
- I'm blaming you. - Yeah.
你们为什么没有及时介入  做点什么呢
Why didn't you step in and do something here?
我们又不知道我们的小孩
Hey, we don't know all the crazy crap
-在做这么疯狂的事情  -也不想知道
- our kids are doing. - We don't want to know.
但我们走进音乐剧演出礼堂时
But I did start to get suspicious
我确实有点起疑心
when we were walking into the fall musical
我在口袋里找到一个奇怪的东西
and I found this weird thing in my pocket.
*音乐剧  音乐剧*
*Musical! Musical!*
*看你们姐姐表演音乐剧*
*Time to watch your sister in a musical!*
咦  我口袋里这是啥
Wait, what's this weird thing in my pocket?
里面见
See you in there!
"诚邀您观赏
"You are invited to attend the performance
吉恩独挑大梁音乐剧
of Die Hard, the Musical,
《虎胆龙威》
A one-Gene show,
就在今晚地下开水房  不见不散"
in the secret boiler room at school tonight."
吉恩也要演音乐剧吗  今晚
Gene's in a musical at school, too? Tonight?
天呐  我们的孩子成竞争对手了
Oh, my God, our kids are in competing musicals!
我一直梦想着这一天的到来
I always dreamed this night would happen.
这是你的梦想
That's your dream?
对  蒂娜成为总统  还有这个
Yeah, Tina's the president and this.
我们中应该有一个去看吉恩的剧
Well, I guess one of us should go to Gene's play.
我选《打工女郎》
I call Working Girl!
好吧  那我去后台祝蒂娜好运
fine, I'll go backstage to wish Tina good luck.
嗨  我的小西格妮・韦弗
Hey, my little Sigourney Weaver-achiever.
《打工女郎》中凯瑟琳・帕克的扮演者
临场恐惧症有犯吗
How's your stage fright, honey?
我刚找到了唯一的良药
It just so happens I found the only cure.
他的翘臀
It's his butt.
爸  乔丝玲的垫肩太大了
Dad, Jocelyn's shoulder pads are too big!
她卡在门框里了
She's stuck in the doorway!
从后面踹她一脚
Just kick her from behind!
我去  剧院的人
Sheesh! Theater people!
总是这么戏剧化
So dramatic.
我爱死了
God, I love it.
*我想唱  我想跳*
*I want to sing, I want to dance*
*我想演  我想演*
*I want to act, I want to play!*
老妈
Mom?
干啥  哦  对不起
Yeah... Oh, sorry.
不能坐  这是卡莉・西蒙的座位
No! This is Carly Simon's seat.
你是卡莉・西蒙吗
Are you Carly Simon?
不是
Uh, no.
我知道你不是
I know you're not!
天  卡莉・西蒙要来吗
Wow. Carly Simon's gonna be here?!
老爸
Psst, Dad!
-咋了  -跟我来
- What? - Come with me.
是你老妈去看吉恩那个啥剧
I think your mom was gonna go to Gene's weird play,
我在这儿看蒂娜表演
and I was gonna stay here and watch Tina.
不是哦
I don't think so.
我们需要你庞大的身躯  让观众席满一点
We need your giant body to make the audience look fuller!
但是《打工女郎》曾经激励我
But Working Girl's the film that inspired me
勇敢找寻真实的自我
to be anything I wanted to be!
结果你就成这样了  来吧  爸
And so you're this? Come on, Dad!
好吧
Fine.
如果你们想看真正无畏的剧目
Hey, if you want to see some real, gritty theater,
就去看地下室的《虎胆龙威》音乐剧吧
we got Die Hard, the Musical down in the basement.
只要五块
Only five bucks!
露易丝  别烦人家
Louise, don't bother these people.
而且反正也没用
Plus, that's not gonna work.
我是《虎胆龙威》铁杆粉丝  看
I'm a Die Hard freak. Check it out.
邦尼・彼地丽娅[麦克莱恩妻子扮演者]
Bonnie Bedelia.
而且我只是某人的叔叔
Also, I'm just an uncle,
不看也没啥
so no biggie.
到了  老板
Here ya go, champ.
我去  这里好热
Geez, it's hot in here.
-那是老鼠吗  -是的
- Whoa, is that a rat? - Yes, it is.
看来鲍勃去看吉恩的演出了
I guess Bob went to Gene's play.
我儿子要演《虎胆龙威》音乐剧
My son's doing Die Hard, the Musical,
在地下室
in the basement.
是竞演剧目
It's a competing musical.
和这部剧竞争
It's competing with this one right now.
你嫉妒我
you're jealous.
*这是一艘船*
This is a boat
*一艘渡船*
*A boat that is a ferry*
*水上的渡船*
*Ferry on the water*
*史丹顿岛渡船*
*Staten Island Ferry*
*我是打工女郎*
*I'm a working girl*
*打工呀嘛女郎*
*A workin' working girl*
*打工的女郎*
*I'm a girl who's working*
*我在*
*I work...*
*纽约打工*
*In New York Ci... ty*
欢迎搭乘纽约到洛杉矶的飞机
All aboard the plane from New York to Los Angeles!
阿盖尔  谢谢你
Thanks, Argyle.
刚才那人说在飞机上该脱鞋
Boy, that guy on the airplane was right
是对的
about taking my shoes off.
*我是光脚警察*
*I'm a barefoot cop... oh!*
*咖啡  咖啡*
*Coffee, coffee*
*我只有咖啡*
*Coffee's all I get*
*如何更进一步*
*How'm I gonna get ahead...*
*请叫我格鲁宾*
*I'm Grubin'*
*我是汉斯・格鲁伯  请叫我格鲁宾*
*I'm Hans Gruber and I'm Grubin'*
《虎胆龙威》中恐怖分子头头
*我这样说时也许意味着我射中了*
*And sometimes that can mean shootin'*
*高木先生的脑袋*
*Mr. Takagi in the head...*
*喂  我是凯瑟琳  你的老板*
*Hey, this is Katherine, you work for me*
*我滑雪时摔断了腿*
*I've broken my leg while trying to ski*
*帮我个忙  代一下班*
*Do me a favor and fill in for me*
*虽然我偷了你为特拉斯科工业公司*
*Even though I stole your radio deal idea*
*想的投资方案*
*For Trask Industries...*
你干了什么
You did what?!
那是我女儿
That's my daughter!
你就是嫉妒
Jealous.
这剧就是
This is everything
如今百老汇败笔的荟萃
that's wrong with Broadway today.
《虎胆龙威》  独角戏  就在地下室
Die Hard, one-man-show, in the basement.
惊爆你的眼球
Blow your mind!
好吧
Okay.
我错过了吉恩的戏
Aw, I'm missing it!
应该可以溜去看看
Maybe I can pop down for a bit.
现在就去
There I go.
*打斗戏  打斗戏*
*Fight scene, fight scene*
*接下来是打斗戏*
*We're gonna have a fight scene*
我的老天
Oh, my God.
借过  借过
'scuse me, eh, 'scuse me.
是吧  他太有才了
I know, right? He's magnificent!
这边好暖和
Ooh, it's warm in here.
露易丝收你五块钱没
Hey, did Louise charge you five bucks?
-收了  -老鼠
- Yes. - Ooh, rat!
*我有商业的头脑*
*I have a head for business*
*和放浪的身体*
*And a bod for sin*
*二者都合我意  让我跟你一起*
*Well I want both, so count me in!*
笑  笑
Smile. Smile!
什么情况
What the hell?
人都去哪儿了  喂  喂
Where is everybody?! Hey, hey, hey!
-你去哪里  -不去哪儿
- Where are you going? - Uh... nowhere.
不是要去地下室看《虎胆龙威》音乐剧
And, uh, not to the Die Hard musical in the basement.
小吉米  演得很棒
Great job, Jimmy Jr.!
谢谢老爸
Thanks, Dad.
卡莉・西蒙呢
Where the hell is Carly Simon?!
她留言了
She, uh, left a message!
说正为了大家赶过来
She's getting drive through... for everyone.
*作为一名警察的老婆*
*Oh, the life of the wife of a cop*
*过着头晕目眩的生活*
*Makes my head spin around like a top...*
交五块
Hey, hey! Five bucks!
怎么回事
What's going on?!
你在演你的《虎胆龙威》
You're doing your Die Hard musical?!
我喜欢霍莉・甄娜罗・麦克莱恩的部分
Oh, I love the Holly Gennaro McClane number.
我去
Oh, my God!
他在跟我们对着干呢
He's musical battling us.
这我见得多了
I've seen it a million times!
停下
Stop it!
不许再唱了
Stop that singing right now!
没人能阻止我儿子唱歌
Nobody tells my son to stop singing!
其实我看得差不多了
Well, actually, I've probably seen enough.
儿子  继续
Keep going, baby!
*约翰・麦克莱恩*
*That Johnny McClane's*
*让我爱得痴狂*
*Driving this gal insane...*
我要让他停下
I'll make him stop.
爸爸  别
Daddy, no!
没错  这人用垫肩砸了我儿子
Yes! That man hit my son with a shoulder pad.
等等
Hold on!
我是凑巧抓了个垫肩
I accidentally grabbed a shoulder pad,
可能是手一滑就飞出去了
maybe it went flying, maybe not.
然后她就冲过来了
And then she came after me!
鲍勃还推了我
And Bob pushed me!
我是把你从琳达跟前推开
Hey, I was just pushing you away from Linda.
她当时快抓狂了
She's crazy.
没错  亲爱的
That's right, honey!
哎哟  我发了
Oh, my God. I'm rich.
-什么  -没什么
- What? - Nothing.
现在我知道所有经过了
Well, I think I've heard everything.
好  那一起去看我的剧的结局吧
Great, let's all go watch the end of my play.
听说终章特别棒
I hear the finale is amazing.
不  去看我的剧
No, no, my play!
没人想看你换假发到处乱窜
Nobody wants to watch you running around changing wigs!
这你应该跟英国议会说去
Tell that to British Parliament!
我得说实话  一个人
I-I have to admit, watching one person
演《虎胆龙威》  确实有点难看
do Die Hard is a little... bad.
爸爸
Father!
喂  吉恩至少天然去修饰
Hey, at least Gene's was raw! From the gut.
考特尼太老练  哪有小孩演成这样
Courtney's was all slick like a kid didn't even do it.
那是因为一般小孩根本达不到这样的水平
That's because a kid could never do it. Never!
是么
Oh, yeah?
我儿子可没有向观众许诺卡莉・西蒙回来
My son's not the one who promised Carly Simon,
最后却放人鸽子
and then left everyone hanging!
她刚给我发短信  说她的车被劫持了
She just texted me that she was car-jacked,
但她说会尽快赶到的
but she's still going to try to make it!
所以应该把我们的剧演完  福旺德先生
So we should finish our play, Mr. Frond.
没错
Yeah!
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
我妈说得对
My mother was right.
搞音乐剧什么的太危险了
This musical theater stuff is just too dangerous.
因此为了大家的安全
So for the safety of everyone,
我宣布  今晚的音乐剧取消了
there will be no more musicals tonight.
也许再也不会有了
And maybe ever!
-啥  -别啊
- What? - No!
虽然不知道我是否有这种权利
I don't know if I have that authority,
但至少今晚是没戏了
but at least for tonight, it's finished.
-别啊  -不要
- Oh, come on! - No!
什么情况
What happened?
还能继续演我们的剧吗
Are we gonna finish the play?
不能  快过来
No, come here.
过来  过来
Come here, come here.
我们能挺过去的
We'll get through this.
我  我不想  不  不必了
I-I-I don't want... No. No, thanks.
好了  该回家了  各位
Okay, time to go home, everyone.
演出结束了
Show's over.
今晚彻底搞砸了
Yeah, the whole night was a bust.
走吧  吉恩  我们回家
Come on, Gene. Let's go home.
等下  福旺德老师
Wait! Mr. Frond!
咋了
What?
我想通了
I guess one boy,
任凭你再有天赋
no matter how talented...
再魅力超凡  人见人爱
and charismatic... and likable...
也无权破坏大家的音乐剧
doesn't have the right to ruin musicals for everyone.
考特尼  继续你的演出吧
So, Courtney, you finish your play.
吉恩
Gene.
真懂事
So noble!
不  吉恩  你说得对
No, Gene. You were right.
我的确偷了你的点子
I did steal your thunder.
《打工女郎》就是《虎胆龙威》的姐妹篇
Working Girl is the sassy sister film to Die Hard.
这已经人尽皆知了
Everybody knows that.
我只是气你不让我参演你的剧
I was just so mad you wouldn't let me be in your play.
其实  我们也许可以合作一下
Well, maybe we can be in each other's plays.
我  啥
I... What?!
给我们三个半小时就好
We just need three and a half hours to prepare.
吉恩  都九点半了  我内裤都湿透了
Gene, it's 9:30, and I have a lot of sweat in my underwear.
好吧好吧
Fine, fine.
给我25分钟
25 minutes.
不行  吉恩  一切都结束了
No way, Gene. This is done.
真可惜
Too bad.
我还觉得刚才的冲突调解堪称史无前例呢
Seems like that conflict resolution could've been epic.
搞不好能得奖的
Maybe award winning.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
你说我会因此荣获"调解达人"称号吗
You think I could win a Conflicty for this?!
当然  "调解达人"非你莫属
Yeah, you could win a Conflicty!
干起来
Let's do it!
好咧  来吧  各位
All right, come on, everybody!
快牵着我的手
Take my hands.
不  等等  等等
No, wait, wait.
我们应该独立完成
We got to do this ourselves.
苔丝・麦吉尔一定也希望这样的
It's what Tess McGill would've wanted.
《打工女郎》女主人公
可考特尼  乖乖
But Courtney, honey...
有时候
Sometimes...
为了打破玻璃天花板
Sometimes to break through the glass ceiling,
你不得不伤一些人的心
you got to break some hearts.
再打碎几块玻璃
And glass.
你应该猜到会吃我一巴掌了吧
You probably think this slap is about you.
虽然不知道我们能不能成功
So I don't know if we can pull this off,
毕竟只排练了20分钟
I mean, we wrote and rehearsed it in under 20 minutes,
但如果成功了
but if we do,
那也是因为我们彼此的参与
it's because we did it together.
是合作的结果
All of us.
男女在合力造人之前
That's exactly what people say
估计也是这么说的
before they make a baby, I think.
好了  废话不多说
Okay, well, without any further ado,
请欣赏浪漫轻喜同人动作惊悚音乐剧
we present to you the musical rom-com-slash-action-thriller,
《姑娘  努力干活  至死方休》
Work Hard or Die Trying, Girl.
别啊
Oh, no!
我们是一群来自纽约的秘书
We're a bunch of secretaries from New York
在中臣大厦被劫为人质
held hostage in Nakatomi Towers!
中臣广场：《虎胆龙威》中被摧毁的大厦
原型为福克斯电影公司总部  福克斯大厦
闭嘴
Shush!
我叫卡尔  长发飘飘
I'm Karl, the one with beautiful hair!
我是汉斯・格鲁伯  你们都完蛋了
I'm Hans Gruber. Consider yourself Grubed!
苔丝・麦吉尔不能让
Tess McGill can't let
几个恐怖分子毁掉她的梦想
a bunch of terrorists ruin her dream.
希望警察赶紧来
I hope the police come soon.
玻璃扎伤了约翰・麦克莱恩的脚
Glass! Hurtin' John McClane's feet!
*我是约翰逊特工*
*I'm Agent Johnson*
*我也是约翰逊特工*
*And I'm Agent Johnson*
*我们来自FBI*
*And we're from the FBI*
*-我是约翰逊 -他是约翰逊*
*- I'm Johnson - He's Johnson!*
*我们是两个脚上功夫了得的联邦官员*
*Two fancy-footed federal guys*
*虽然我只是个当地的小警员*
*I might just be a local cop*
*但你们能别来烦我不*
*But will you guys back off me?*
*气氛貌似有点僵*
*Things are getting pretty tense*
*有人想来杯咖啡不*
*Does anybody want coffee?*
其实  我两之间并没那么多不同的
You know we're not so different, you and I.
*我们都野心勃勃  汉斯*
*We're both ambitious, Hans*
苔丝・麦吉尔  你已偷走我的心
Tess McGill, you've stolen this Gruber's heart.
*-就像你偷走  -就像我偷走*
*- Like I'm stealing - Like you're stealing*
*那些债券*
*These bearer bonds*
*我破解密  码啦*
*I cracked the co... de*
给  债券
So here's the bearer bonds.
也就相当于现金
Which is the same as money, I guess.
我们现在可以投资电台啦
Hey, let's make that radio deal.
嘻哈如何
Hip hop?
嘻哈
Hip hop.
剧本里没这个啊
That's not in the script.
随它去吧  观众就爱这个
Just go with it... they love it!
你是长了两排门牙么
Is that two rows of teeth I'm feeling?
我的乳齿一直没掉
My baby teeth never fell out.
现在我和杰克・特雷纳也成一对啦
And Jack Trainer and I are a couple now as well,
《打工女郎》中角色
这样很好  嘻哈  嘻哈
so that's good. Hip hop. Hip hop.
*汉斯  你已感受到爱情的伟大*
*Hans, you're feeling love's great power*
*但我还是要将你推下大厦*
*But now I got to push you off the tower!*
快过来  我来抓你了
Now come here. I'm gonna get ya.
过来
Come on.
我太生我兄弟的气了
I'm so mad about my brother
所以我要杀了你
so I kill you about it!
不
No...!
谢啦  兄弟
Thanks, Al!
这世上要是有个
If only there was a place
人人都能幸福而不用被杀的地方就好了
where we could all be happy and not get killed!
*在那高空*
*Maybe there's a tower*
*或许有这么一座大厦*
*Somewhere up above*
*里面装满了爱和债券*
*Filled with bearer bonds and love*
*梦想也能够实现*
*Where dreams don't die hard*
*在那高空*
*Maybe there's a tower*
*或许有这么一座大厦*
*Somewhere up above*
*里面装满了爱和垫肩*
*Filled with shoulder pads and love*
*梦想也能展翅高飞*
*Where dreams can fly hard*
*但在我们找到那想象中的天堂前*
*But until we can live in that imaginary world*
*姑娘  我们努力干活  至死方休*
*We'll work hard or die trying, girl.*
太棒了  太棒了
Yes! Yes!
我去
Oh, my God!
你是卡莉・西蒙
Carly Simon?
谁
Who?
抱歉  你  你
Oh, sorry. Y-You...
你长得好像卡莉・西蒙
you look like Carly Simon.
你才像卡莉・西蒙呢
You look like Carly Simon.
我这是在夸你
It's a compliment.
离我远点
Back off.
对不起了  我天
Sorry. Geez.
我嗅到托尼奖的味道了
I smell a Tony!
也恰巧是我的屁味
Which is also what happens to be what I call my farts.
*努力干活*
*Work hard... *
*至死方休*
*Or die trying*
*努力干活  至死方休*
*Ooh, you work hard, you die hard*
*努力干活*
*Work hard*
*至死方休*
*You work hard!*
来啊  来啊
Come on, come on!
*至死方休  姑娘*
*Or die trying, girl*
*努力干活 至死方休*
*You work hard, you try hard*
*努力干活*
*Work hard*
*至死方休*
*Or die trying, girl*
*努力干活 至死方休*
*You work hard, you die hard*
*努力干活*
*Work hard*
*不不不不*
*No, no, no, no, no*
*努力干活  至死方休 姑娘*
*Work hard... Or die trying, girl*